Writing is only part of the annual process.
Once the OP1 document has been completed,
the readers, typically senior leaders, now assume the primary role.
Their job is to critically read the plan, ask probing questions,
provide constructive feedback, discuss and debate controversial topics,
and ultimately make company-wide decisions on which initiatives to greenlight
at a given funding level.
As a senior leader, reading an OP1 document,
ask yourself these questions while reading,
and enter your answers in the document directly,
or ask them once the discussion begins.
The first question is, do I clearly understand
how this team will create additional customer value next year?
Am I looking at the right input and output metrics?
If not, which ones are missing or incorrect?
Is the detailed wording of each metric exactly what we want?
Do any of these initiatives or goals merit dedicated time
from the executive team to review throughout the year?
If so, these will become S-team goals, which we will cover in the next lesson.
Does the team have too many or too few resources
to accomplish each of the work streams and initiatives outlined in the plan?
Is the team thinking big enough?
Do they have the right mix of activities, including bold bets,
improving the core business, and fixing paper cuts?
Where are the risks with this plan?
Have they been identified and properly mitigated?
Are there any dependencies on my organization?
If so, has someone from my organization reviewed them,
and are they accurate?
For each initiative, are all of the dependencies called out and resolved?
Are these the most important initiatives that will move the needle
in a meaningful way for this business?
Are the team's key assumptions true?
A good technique to answer this question is to look at the inverse case.
Try to find any case where the assumption is not true.
And finally, you do not want to leave the room
until the answer to the following question is yes.
Do I believe that these initiatives and input goals
can be met with the requested investment of resources,
and if they are met, will we hit our output goals?
As you ask questions, be direct and constructive.
Ask questions that will drive deeper thinking.
The ultimate goal is to leave the room with a solid plan.
The Presenters:
At minimum, the presenters, who are the team that wrote the document,
needs to include the business unit leader, key team members,
one of whom is the designated note taker,
the finance counterpart, and representatives from any other team
that have big dependencies that will invest significant resources
in any part of the proposed initiatives.
And lastly, the HR lead for the group.
Make sure you have access to any supplemental data or documents,
not in the OP1 plan, that could be helpful.
Examples of this include last year's OP1 plan,
your latest QBR or MBR,
your latest weekly business review or WBR,
detailed customer demographic and usage data and so forth.
The note taker cannot be the primary person who answers questions
in a meeting, and they need to be a team member who is deeply
familiar with the details of the business, not an admin.
Make sure to answer all questions concisely and with data.
If you don't know the answer, and no one else from your team does either,
then say you don't know and I will get back to you.
This last tip is easier said than done, but is largely under your control.
Oh, and finally, make sure you get a good night's sleep
the night before the meeting.
The meeting should last 90 to 120 minutes.
If your business area is complex or large,
and you can't fit at all into that time,
make sure you create separate documents for those parts of your business
and allocate separate meeting slots for them.
In most cases, for an Amazon meeting,
the document is six pages long plus appendices.
We would allocate 60 minutes for the meeting,
where 15 minutes could be reading time,
and the rest of the time was available for discussion.
OP1 meetings and documents are more complex.
We would still have the limit of six pages and appendices,
but the difference is that we would allow more time for the meeting itself
because the discussion would be longer,
hence the 90 to 120 minute timing.
We would also have time to leave slack time between meetings.
Not only can the meetings get spirited
and downtime is necessary in between,
but more importantly, new issues would surface during the OP1 review,
and it would take longer than expected to resolve those issues.
At Amazon, we favored letting the meeting run over its allocated time
because we had all the right people in the room,
and it was much easier to keep the meeting going
than to schedule a second meeting.
The OP1 plan is not going to be approved at the end of the meeting
because the company has a constrained set of resources
and the executive team needs to review all OP1 plans
before deciding how to allocate those scarce resources.